Guide to the New York State Democratic Committee records
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
New York State Democratic Committee Records
1970-2007
[Bulk Dates: 1990-2004].
New York State Democratic Committee.
19.01 linear feet ( 27 document boxes, 2 record cartons, 4 photo boxes, 4 oversize flat boxes, 3 scroll boxes).
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library, New York, NY. 10027
6217608
The New York State Democratic Committee (NYSDC) is the official organization of the Democratic Party in the State of New York. The NYSDC adopts and approves changes in the rules that govern party membership, meetings, delegates, conventions, nominations, campaigns, and other functions that take place within the Democratic Party.
Historical Note
The New York State Democratic Committee (NYSDC) is the official organization of the Democratic Party in the State of New York. The NYSDC adopts and approves changes in the rules that govern party membership, meetings, delegates, conventions, nominations, campaigns, and other functions that take place within the Democratic Party.
Scope and Content
This collection includes administrative correspondence, photographs, audiovisual recordings, and ephemera that documents the Democratic Party, particularly as it exists in New York State. The bulk of the documentation relates to elections and to the State Committee's administration of the Party, but there are also records relating to national political processes.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in four series.
Series I: Files, 1980-2006
Subseries I.1: General, 1980-2006
Subseries I.2: Conventions, 1990-2006
Subseries I.3: Delegates and Electoral College, 1991-2004
Subseries I.4: Elections and Campaigns, 1990-2004
Subseries I.5: Judicial, 1988-2006
Subseries I.6: State Committee, 1990-2006
Series II: Audiovisual, 1996-2004
Subseries II.1: Videotapes, 1996-2004
Subseries II.2: Audiotapes, 1998-2002
Subseries II.3: CDs, 2002-2004
Series III: Photographs, 1970-2006
Series IV: Ephemera, 1996-2007
Subseries IV.1: Printed Material, 1996-2007
Subseries IV.2: Realia, 1996-2004
Subjects
Democrat National Committee.; Democratic Party (N.Y.); Democratic Party (N.Y.).--State Convention.; Democratic Party (N.Y.).--State Convention--(1998: Rye Brook); Democratic Party (N.Y.).--State Convention--(2000); Democratic Party (N.Y.).--State Convention--(2002); Democratic Party (N.Y.).--State Convention--(2006); New York (State).--Governor.; New York (State).--Senator.; Clinton, Bill, 1946-; Clinton, Hillary Rodham.; Gore, Albert, 1948-; Kerry, John, 1943-; Pataki, George E., 1945-; Spitzer, Eliot.; Election districts--New York (State)--Statistics.; Elections--United States.; Electoral college.; Electoral college--United States.
Access Restrictions
This collection has no restrictions.
This collection is located off-site. You will need to request this material at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
Acquisition
New York State Democratic Committee Donation, June 2007.
Finding aid in repository; folder level control.
- Series I: Files, 1980-2006
  This series is comprised of documentation regarding various aspects of the political process in the United States, particularly as it relates to New York State's Democrats.
  - Subseries I.1: General, 1980-2005
    This subseries is comprised of logistical and statistical information related to the functioning of political parties within the United States and especially within New York State. The folders within this subseries contain information that is not directly related to the State Democratic Committee, but involves members of the Democratic Party or issues that confront it. Many of these folders are related to individual counties in New York State or to financial records kept by the party.
    - General, 1980s-2000s, (2 folders) (Box 1)
    - 1792 Club, 2000s (Box 1)
    - Association of State Democratic Chairs, 2002 (Box 1)
    - Board of Elections Certification Lists, 2004 (Box 1)
    - Board of Election Notices, 2006 (Box 1)
    - Budget and Finances, 2000, (2 folders) (Box 1)
    - Civil Marriage Resolution, 2003 (Box 1)
    - College Democrats, 2005 (Box 2)
    - Correspondence, 1980s-2000s, (2 folders) (Box 2)
    - County Chairs, 2000s (Box 2)
    - County Chairs Resources, 2000s (Box 2)
    - County Committee Correspondence, 1999 (Box 2)
    - Democratic Governor’s Association, 1996 (Box 2)
    - DNC, 2000s (Box 2)
    - Democratic Rural Conference, 1999 (Box 2)
    - Dis/Approved Correspondence, 1996 (Box 2)
    - Donors, 1989-1995 (Box 3)
    - Executive Committee Conference Calls, 1990s-2000s (Box 3)
    - Executive Committee Proxies, 1995 (Box 3)
    - Financial, 1990s (Box 3)
    - Flight Dates, 1999 (Box 3)
    - FOIA Requests, 2000s (Box 3)
    - Governor’s Vote By Assembly District, 1998 (Box 3)
    - Herman "Denny" Farrell Jr. Correspondence, 2000s (Box 3)
    - Matching Grants, 2004 (Box 3)
    - Members of DNC, 1990s-2000s (Box 3)
    - Nassau Democratic Action Plan, 2001 (Box 3)
    - National Hispanic/Latino American Agenda Summit, 2004 (Box 3)
    - Resolutions, 2004 (Box 4)
    - Rockland County Insurance Contracts, 2004 (Box 4)
    - Rules and Certification of Officers, 1995-2001 (Box 4)
    - Rules and Regulations, 2005 (Box 4)
    - Somos El Futura, 2004 (Box 4)
    - Standing Committee, 2004 (Box 4)
    - Tax Return Press Conference, 2000 (Box 4)
    - Town Chairs, 2004 (Box 4)
    - Treasury, 1999 (Box 4)
    - Vacancies and Replacement, 1990s-2000s (Box 4)
    - Vacancies, 2002 (Box 4)
    - VIP Mailings, 1997 (Box 4)
    - Website Proposals, 2003 (Box 4)
    - Young Democrats, 2000s (Box 4)
  - Subseries I.2: Conventions, 1990-2006
    The bulk of the convention files is concerned with New York State Democratic conventions, although there is some information about national conventions for the Democratic and Republican parties. Many of the conventions held between 1990 and 2006 are included in the records of sign-in sheets, hotel plans, proxy forms, correspondence, rules and regulations, and plans for important election years. The state conventions of 1998, 2000, 2002, and 2006 are the most extensively covered.
    - Democratic National Convention (Box 5)
      - 1992 (Box 5)
      - 1996, (2 folders) (Box 5)
      - 2000 (Box 5)
      - 2004 (Box 5)
    - RNC, 2004 (Box 6)
    - New York State Convention
      - 1990 (Box 6)
      - 1992 (Box 6)
      - 1994 (Box 6)
      - 1998, (6 folders) (Box 6)
      - 2000, (4 folders) (Box 7)
      - 2002, (4 folders) (Box 7)
      - 2004 (Box 8)
      - 2006, (3 folders) (Box 8)
      - Brochures, 1998-2002 ( 2 folders) (Box 8)
  - Subseries I.3: Delegates and Electoral College, 1991-2004
    This small subseries includes information regarding delegate selection and the role of the Electoral College in elections. Prominently featured are statements of candidacy, as well as official DNC rules and regulations for selecting delegates.
    - Delegate Selection and Affirmative Action Plan, 1991 (Box 9)
    - Electoral College, 1996, (2 folders) (Box 9)
    - Statement of Candidacy, 1999-2000, (3 folders) (Box 9)
    - Certificate of Ascertainment and Certificate of Vote, 2000 (Box 37)
    - Delegates and Alternates, 2000 (Box 9)
    - Delegate Plan, 2000 (Box 9)
    - Electoral College 2001, (2 folders) (Box 10)
    - Delegates and Delegate Information, 2004 (Box 10)
    - Delegation Meeting, 2004 (Box 10)
    - DNC Rules and By-Laws and Delegate Selection Plan, 2004 (Box 10)
  - Subseries I.4: Elections and Campaigns, 1990-2004
    A major aim of the New York State Democratic Committee is to elect Democrats into political offices throughout the state. This subseries chronicles recent elections. Extensive coverage is given to the senate election of 2000 between Hillary Rodham Clinton and Rick Lazio and to polling throughout this eight year span. Advertisements and media coverage or relations for other statewide elections, local elections throughout the state, and national elections are also included.
    - Budget and Finances, 1998 (Box 10)
    - Budgeting and Races, 1990s-2000s (Box 10)
    - Campaign Ads, 1990s-2000s (Box 11)
    - Campaign Manual, undated (Box 11)
    - County Surveys, 1990s-2000s, (4 folders) (Box 11)
    - General Election, 1990s-2000s (Box 12)
    - Events and Fundraisers, 1990s-2000s, (2 folders) (Box 12)
    - Fossella, Vita 1997 (Box 12)
    - Legal Framework, 1990s-2000s (Box 12)
    - Literature/Mailings, 2000s (Box 12)
    - New York State Board of Elections, 2001 (Box 12)
    - Pataki and D’Amato, 1997-2000 (Box 12)
    - Victory Fund, 2000-2004 (Box 12)
    - 1996 (Box 13)
      - Analysis of NYSDC 1996 Campaign (Box 13)
    - 1997
      - Campaign Manual (Box 13)
      - Federal Election Campaign Laws (Box 13)
      - Statewide Media Planning Guides (Box 13)
    - 1998
      - Ballot (Box 13)
      - Ballot Summaries (Box 13)
      - Coordinated Campaign (Box 13)
      - Coordinated Campaign – Finances (Box 13)
      - Election (Box 13)
      - Election Media and Polling (Box 14)
      - NYSDC TV Buy Plans
        - 1998 September 21-27 (Box 14)
        - 1998 October 5-6 (Box 14)
        - 1998 October 8-11 (Box 14)
        - 1998 October 12-14 (Box 14)
      - New York State Elections (Box 14)
      - Phone Survey Questionnaires (Box 14)
      - Radio Buy Plans (Box 15)
      - Victory 1998
        - General (Box 15)
        - Cash Flow (Box 15)
        - Literature and Scripts (Box 15)
        - Post-Campaign Analysis (Box 15)
    - 1999
      - Campaign Training Workshop (Box 15)
      - Elections (Box 15)
      - Post-Campaign Analysis (Box 15)
      - Rockland County Special Senate Election (Box 15)
      - TV Buy Plans, 1999 November 25-December 1 (Box 15)
      - "We Vote, We Win" (Box 15)
      - "Winning Local Elections in 1999" (Box 15)
    - 2000 (Box 16)
      - Banner Book Addendum (Box 16)
      - Democratic National Platform (Box 16)
      - GOTV (Box 16)
      - Literature (Box 16)
      - Media Strategies and Research (Box 16)
      - New York CD 1 Survey (Box 16)
      - Polling, (2 folders) (Box 16)
      - Poll Verbatim Response (Box 16)
      - Primary and Election Votes (Box 16)
      - New York State Senate Race (Box 17)
      - New York Senate Events, (2 folders) (Box 17)
      - Senate Race 2000 Statement of Support for Hillary Clinton, (2 folders) (Box 17)
      - Statewide Survey Conducted November 2000 (Box 17)
    - Victory 2000
      - General (Box 17)
      - Coordinated Campaign Plan (Box 17)
      - Issue Ads, (2 folders) (Box 18)
      - Legal (Box 18)
      - Mailings (Box 18)
    - 2001
      - Action Plan (Box 18)
      - GOTV (Box 18)
    - 2002
      - Campaign Plan New York (Box 18)
      - March 2 Primary (Box 18)
      - Radio Ads (Box 18)
      - Special Election (Box 18)
      - State Party Ads (Box 18)
      - Survey and Invoice (Box 18)
      - Surveys (Box 18)
      - Victory 2002 Coordinated Campaign Plan (Box 18)
    - 2003
      - Blastfaxes (Box 18)
      - Estrada Nomination (Box 18)
      - New York Citywide Survey, 2003 April (Box 19)
      - Nonpartisan Election Proposal, (2 folders) (Box 19)
    - 2004
      - Coordinated Campaign - Election Day (Box 19)
      - Events (Box 19)
      - GOTV (Box 19)
      - Primary Election Congressional Districts
        - 5-7 (Box 19)
        - 8-9 (Box 19)
        - 10-12 (Box 19)
        - 13-15 (Box 19)
        - 16-17 (Box 19)
      - Spanish Ads (Box 19)
      - Vendor Table Info (Box 19)
      - Victory 2004 (Box 20)
      - Victory Coordinated Campaign, (2 folders) (Box 20)
      - Working Families Party Acceptance (Box 20)
  - Subseries I.5: Judicial, 1988-2006
    This subseries is almost wholly comprised of information regarding Judicial Nominating Conventions in New York State between 1994 and 2006. Every year between 1997 and 2006 has its own folder, which contains general information about the convention. A party call is also available for every year starting in 1994 and ending in 2005.
    - General, 2000s (Box 20)
    - Judicial Screening Supreme Court, 2000s (Box 20)
    - Judicial Nominating Conventions
      - General, 1988-1997 (Box 20)
      - 1997 (Box 20)
      - 1998 (Box 20)
      - 1999 (Box 20)
      - 2000 (Box 21)
      - 2001 (Box 21)
      - 2002 (Box 21)
      - 2003 (Box 21)
      - 2004 (Box 21)
      - 2005 (Box 21)
      - 2006 (Box 21)
    - Party Call
      - 1994 (Box 21)
      - 1995 (Box 21)
      - 1996 (Box 21)
      - 1997 (Box 21)
      - 1998 (Box 21)
      - 1999 (Box 21)
      - 2000 (Box 21)
      - 2001 (Box 21)
      - 2002 (Box 21)
      - 2003 (Box 21)
      - 2004 (Box 21)
      - 2005 (Box 21)
  - Subseries I.6: State Committee, 1990-2004
    The State Committee subseries deals largely with the New York State Democratic Committee’s biannual meetings between 1995 and 2004. The subseries holds more detailed information in regards to scheduling and logistics about the meetings than information about substantive policies and strategy discussed; however, minutes are included in the material corresponding to most meetings.
    - General, 1998-2000, (2 folders) (Box 22)
    - Conference Calls, 2004 (Box 22)
    - Lease, 1997 (Box 22)
    - Lists, 1990s-2000s, (3 folders) (Box 22)
    - List Updates, 1990s-2000s (Box 22)
    - Logo, undated (Box 22)
    - State Nominating Convention 2004 (Box 23)
    - State Party Operations Brochure, undated (Box 23)
    - State Committee Retreat, 1996 (Box 23)
    - State Committee Meeting/Proxies
      - Meeting, 1995 Spring (Box 23)
      - Proxies, 1995 Spring (Box 23)
      - Meeting, 1997 Spring (Box 23)
      - Proxies, 1997 Spring (Box 23)
      - Roll Call, 1997 Fall (Box 23)
      - Meeting, 1998 Spring (Box 23)
      - Meeting,1998 Fall, (3 folders) (Box 24)
      - Meeting, 1999 Spring (Box 24)
      - Members, 1999 (Box 24)
      - Roll Call and Sign-in Sheet, 1999 Spring (Box 24)
      - Meeting, 1999 Fall (Box 24)
      - Proxies, 1999 Fall (Box 24)
      - Meeting, 2000 Fall, (2 folders) (Box 25)
      - Proxies, 2000 Fall, (2 folders) (Box 25)
      - Meeting, 2001 Spring, (2 folders) (Box 25)
      - Proxies, 2001 Spring, (2 folders) (Box 25)
      - Vacancies, 2001 Spring (Box 26)
      - Meeting, 2001 Fall (Box 26)
      - Sign-in Sheet, 2001 Fall (Box 26)
      - Meeting, 2002 Fall (Box 26)
      - Members, 2002 Fall (Box 26)
      - Minutes, 2002 Fall (Box 26)
      - Meeting, 2003 Fall, (2 folders) (Box 26)
      - Proxies, 2003 Fall, (2 folders) (Box 27)
      - Meeting, 2004 Fall (Box 27)
      - Members, 2004 Fall (Box 27)
      - Minutes, 2004 Fall (Box 27)
      - State Committee Appointed, 2004 (Box 27)
- Series II: Audiovisual, 1996-2004
  This series includes video tapes, CDs, and audiotapes that cover a variety of topics related to the New York State Democratic Committee, including events and advertisements.
  - Subseries II.1: Videotapes, 1996-2004
    In this subseries, the State Democratic Convention of May 2002 is covered extensively, as is the New York State Senate race of 2000. Many of the videotapes are campaign advertisements.
    - "A+ Education," "Safe Schools," "What’s at Stake?" undated (Box 28)
    - The Abraham Fund Makes it Possible, 1999 October 20 (Box 28)
    - Ads, undated (Box 28)
    - The Al Gore Story, undated (Box 28)
    - America’s Values for the 21st Century, undated (Box 28)
    - Axelrod & Associates, undated (Box 28)
    - "A Celebration of Democracy:" Ohio Democratic Party State Dinner, 1999 (Box 28)
    - "College," 1998 October 16 (Box 28)
    - "College," "Shots," "Lunch," 1998 September 27 (Box 28)
    - Competitive Commercials, undated (Box 28)
    - Comptroller Jobs for New Yorkers, 2002 September 4 (Box 28)
    - Convention 2002 May 22-23
      - TV Promo: Herman "Denny" Farrell, Jr. (Box 28)
      - Day 1, Reel 1 (Box 28)
      - Day 1, Reel 2 (Box 28)
      - Day 1, Reel 3 (Box 28)
      - Day 2, First Half (Box 28)
      - Day 2, Second Half (Box 28)
    - "Cut," "Double," undated (Box 28)
    - Delivering a Message: In Person and On the Radio, Victory 96, 1996 (Box 28)
    - Democratic Convention, 2004 May 18 (Box 28)
    - Democratic Convention video, undated (Box 28)
    - Democratic State Convention: Remarks by Vice-President Al Gore, undated (Box 28)
    - Democratic Debates, Albany, 1998 (Box 28)
    - "The Democratic Party-America’s Values for the 21st Century," 1997 October 6 (Box 28)
    - "Downstate," "Upstate," undated (Box 28)
    - The Eleanor Roosevelt Legacy Committee, "The Presidential Delegate Selection Process in New York State," 2003 September 30 (Box 28)
    - First Lady Hillary Rodham Clinton, 2000 December 11 (Box 28)
    - "Future," 1999 November 9 (Box 28)
    - "History in the Making," 2000 May 16 (Box 28)
    - "Hold Down," 2000 September 27 (Box 28)
    - "It’s a Sin to Tell a Lie" Test TV Spot, 1998 (Box 28)
    - "Line Rev," "Street," 2000 August 24 (Box 28)
    - "List," 2000 July 22 (Box 28)
    - Liz Krueger, "Why On Earth," "Breast Cancer," "Drug Laws," "Education," 2002 January 18 (Box 28)
    - Liz Krueger for New York State Senate, 2002 January 30 (Box 28)
    - "Lunch," undated (Box 28)
    - "Lunch," undated (Box 28)
    - "Make," 2000 July 11 (Box 28)
    - Mission not Accomplished for America’s Middle Class, 2004 August 30 (Box 28)
    - "Needs," 2000 July 25 (Box 29)
    - "Now," "Buff," 2000 September 19 (Box 29)
    - On the Campaign Trail With Bill Bradley, April Update, (2000 April) (Box 29)
    - On the Campaign Trail With Bill Bradley, July Update, (2000 July) (Box 29)
    - "Quit," 2000 September 6 (Box 29)
    - "Record," 2000 July 19 (Box 29)
    - "Republican Broken Promises," undated (Box 29)
    - "Right," "Real," undated (Box 29)
    - Save Our Environment auction ad, 2001 June 26 (Box 29)
    - Schumer ’98, 1998 October 7 (Box 29)
    - Senator David A. Paterson Welcome Tape, undated (Box 29)
    - "Shell Game," 1999 September 28 (Box 29)
    - "Stand," 2000 August 28 (Box 29)
    - "Stop," 2000 October 18 (Box 29)
    - "This Is George W. Bush’s Texas," undated (Box 29)
    - "Time," "Auction," undated (Box 29)
    - Syracuse 2001 Mayoral Race, 2001 September 5 (Box 29)
    - "Tax Machine," 1999 August 31 (Box 29)
    - "Vote," 1998 September 24 (Box 29)
    - "Vote," 2002 October 29 (Box 29)
    - "Wonder," 2000 July 31 (Box 29)
    - 2000 Compilation Reel, 35 spots, by Jennifer Burton, 2000 November 10 (Box 29)
  - Subseries II.2: Audiotapes, 1998-2002
    The eleven audiotapes included in this collection all focus on elections, especially the gubernatorial election of 1998 and the senate election of 2000. Most of the tapes contain advertisements against Republican governor George Pataki.
    - "Daughter," 1998 (Box 29)
    - Ethnic Targeted Ads, 1998 (Box 29)
    - "Fireworks," 2000 (Box 29)
    - Governor Carey Ad for Pataki, 2001 (Box 29)
    - "Health," undated (Box 29)
    - "Let’s Find Out," Governor Pataki Running for Second Term, undated (Box 29)
    - May 16th Crowd, undated (Box 29)
    - "Moving Away," undated (Box 29)
    - NY Democratic Party, undated (Box 29)
    - NYS PSA, undated (Box 29)
    - Radio Spot, Robocall-Clinton, 2002 (Box 29)
  - Subseries II. 3: CDs, 2002-2004
    The four CDs in the collection, like the audiotapes, appear to be focused on election material.
    - "Clinton GOTV," 2002 (Box 29)
    - "Cuomo," 2002 (Box 29)
    - DNC Photos, 2004 (Box 29)
    - My Dems Jefferson Jackson, 2004 (Box 29)
- Series III: Photographs, 1970-2006
  Most of the events the photographs were taken at seem to have taken place in New York State. Represented in these photographs are notable state and national Democrats, such as the Clintons, Eliot Spitzer, and Al Gore. There are also group shots from state conventions and other events sponsored by the state’s Democratic Committee.
  - Index to Photographs (Box 3)
  - Abzug, 1970s (oversize) (Box 35)
  - Albany Police Pipes and Drums, 2000 (Box 30)
  - Antonio Burgos, 2000 (Box 30)
  - Campaign Training Workshop, 1999 (Box 30)
  - Choir, 2000 (Box 30)
  - Hillary Clinton at Podium, 2000 (Box 30)
  - Clinton and Gore Campaign Office, 1996 (Box 30)
  - Clintons at Podium, 2000 (Box 30)
  - Clintons Greeting Crowd, 2000 (Box 30)
  - Clintons Greeting Guests, 2000 (Box 30)
  - Clinton Inaugural, 1996 (Box 34)
  - Clintons, Kerrick, and Port Authority Police Department, 2000s and (Box 35)
    - Bill Clinton at Ground Breaking, undated (oversize) (Box 35)
  - Clintons, Schumer, Moynihan at Podium, 2000 (Box 30)
  - Clintons with NYSDC members, 2000 (oversize) (Box 36)
  - Clintons with NYSDC members, 2000 (oversize) (Box 37)
  - Clintons’ Welcome Home after Bush Inauguration, 2001 (oversize) (Box 35)
  - Crowd Shots, 2000 (Box 30)
  - Andrew Cuomo, 2000 (Box 30)
  - Cuomo, New York Presidential Forum with George McGovern, Alan Cranston, Ernest Hollings, John Glenn, Gary Hart, Walter Mondale, 1983, undated (oversize) (Box 35)
  - December Party, 2006 (Box 34)
  - Denny’s Birthday, 2006 (Box 30)
  - Ducasse Dinner, 2003 (Box 34)
  - Estrada Nomination, [2003] (Box 30)
  - Fernando Ferrer 1199 SEIU-United Healthcare Workers East, 2005 (Box 31)
  - Fundraiser at Patricia Duff and Ron Perelman’s House, 1995 (Box 31)
  - General, 2000 (Box 31)
  - General, [2000s] (Box 34)
  - General, undated, 2000s (Box 31)
  - General Group Shots, 1996, undated (oversize) (Box 35)
  - General Podium Shots, 2000 (Box 31)
  - Gore, 1997 (oversize) (Box 35)
  - Gore at McCall Event, 2003 (Box 34)
  - Gore, Schumer, Rangel, Moynihan at Podium, 2000 (Box 32)
  - Group Shots Featuring Hillary Clinton, 2000 (Box 32)
  - Holiday Party, 2004 (Box 34)
  - HRC Luncheon, 2003 (Box 34)
  - JJ Dinner, 2003 (Box 34)
  - Judith Hope and Denny Ferrell, 2000 (Box 32)
  - Labor Luncheon, 2003 (Box 34)
  - Labor Luncheon, 2006 (Box 32)
  - March Gala, 2002 (Box 32)
  - McCall, undated (oversize) (Box 35)
  - McCall at Podium, 2000 (Box 32)
  - McCall, Baronella, Moynahan, 2000 (Box 32)
  - NY Dem Convention, 1998 (Box 32)
  - NY Dems Holiday Party, 2002 (Box 33)
  - NY Dems Holiday Party, 2005 (Box 33)
  - NY Dems Labor Luncheon, 2004 (Box 33)
  - NYSDC 2004 Election Shots (oversize) (Box 36)
  - Reception for Eliot Spitzer, 2004 (Box 33)
  - Sheldon Silver, undated (oversize) (Box 35)
  - Sheldon Silver Reception, 2004 (Box 33)
  - Elliot Spitzer, 2000 (Box 33)
  - Spitzers, undated (oversize) (Box 35)
  - Stephanopoulos, undated (oversize) (Box 35)
  - John Sullivan, undated (Box 33)
  - Tavern on the Green
    - General, 2002 (Box 33)
    - John Kerry and NYSDC Members, [2000s] (oversize) (Box 35)
    - John Kerry and NYSDC Members, [2000s] (oversize) (Box 37)
    - Group Shots, undated (oversize) (Box 36)
  - Trustee’s Event, 2003 (Box 33)
  - Victory 2002 NYSD Convention Group Shot, 2002 (oversize) (Box 35)
  - Victory 2002 NYSD Convention Group Shots, 2002 (oversize) (Box 36)
- Series IV: Ephemera, 1996-2007
  This series includes banners, posters, bumper sticks, and pins from major elections, including Hillary Clinton’s reelection campaign and the bids that both Gore and Kerry made for the presidency.
  - Subseries IV.1: Printed Material, 1996-2007
    Most of the materials in this subseries are stored in oversize Boxes, and are related to major elections. There are also a few posters regarding Democratic conventions. Many of the materials are not dated.
    - America 2004 the Democratic Convention, 2004 (oversize) (Box 37)
    - The Blue Fund: Investing in Change We Can Believe In (oversize) (Box 39)
    - Craig Johnson: Democrat for State Senate, 2007 (oversize) (Box 37)
    - Goodbye Pataki!/Adiós Pataki!, 2006 (oversize) (Box 37)
    - New York Democrats (oversize) (Box 40)
    - New York Democrats (oversize) (Box 41)
    - New York State Democratic Committee (oversize) (Box 41)